all right
[Music]
completely plant-based diet is suitable
during pregnancy lactation infancy and
childhood a position echoed by the
oldest and largest Association nutrition
Professionals in the world
ask a couple hundred health
professionals though and as few as one
in three appear to know it like any diet
during pregnancy though it should be
well planned which means consuming large
amounts in a wide variety of plant foods
from all the plant food groups including
whole grains legumes like soybeans
regular beans split peas chickpeas and
lentils vegetables fruits and nuts and
seeds make sure to get enough calcium
from healthy plant-based sources and
sufficient vitamin D from sun or
supplements and critically important
make sure you get a regular reliable
source of vitamin B12 I have a video
about B12 in pregnancy and for kids here
the two books I recommend for raising
plant-based families published by two of
my favorite evidence-based dietitians
are your complete vegan pregnancy by
Reed mangles and nourish co-authored by
Brenda Davis
what data do we have on the impact of
vegan diet and pregnancy outcomes the
vegans had a significantly lower
gestational weight gain by about six
pounds and lower birth weights but just
by a few hundred grams both about seven
pounds each within the normal range with
no differences in the rate of preterm
birth nor any significant differences in
the umbilical cord blood B12 folate or
iron marker levels between the study
groups not surprisingly since the vast
majority of both groups were taking
prenatal vitamins as they should
what about the composition of breast
milk from those eating vegan or
vegetarian diets the systematic review
has shown that all non-vegetarian
vegetarian and vegan mothers produce
breast milk of comparable nutritional
value even Omega-3s there was no
difference in milk DHA composition by
diet group but that's not saying much
since over 80 percent of study
participants had milk concentrations at
long chain omega-3 DHA below Target I
talk about the best way to get pollutant
free sources in a previous video which
we'll link down in the doctor's note on
nutritionfacts.org or in the description
on YouTube
the meat and egg Industries like to
scare Monger about choline but wait this
study was written by someone with no
conflicts of interest
liar here's a corrected version the
competing interest section has been
updated and surprise surprise the author
is a member of a meat industry-funded
advisory panel the truth is there's just
as much choline in the breast milk of
vegans as those who eat eggs or meat
there is something egg free meat-free
Mothers may not be passing on as much
though industrial pollutants like the
banned pesticide DDT in cancer-causing
pcbs the highest levels were found in
the milk of Fish Eaters and the lowest
levels found in vegetarians even just
cutting out meat may cut DDT stores in
half for example here's the level of
pesticides and carcinogenic pcbs found
in the breast milk from two sisters with
different dietary habits the levels of
DDT DDE a breakdown product of DDT
deodorant and beta hexachloro
cyclohexane two other banned pesticides
as well as pcbs were much lower in the
milk fat from the lacto-vegetarian
mother than in that from the
non-vegetarian sister that's because
these chemicals build up the food chain
and animal fat our fat as well as any
animal fat we eat
what about mothers who eat strictly
plant-based their milk is even less
polluted for almost every contaminant
there was no overlap in the range of
scores meaning the highest worst
vegetarian value was lower than the best
lowest value obtained in the U.S sample
and by vegetarian here if they mean
women who eliminate all animal products
from their diets including eggs and
Dairy the one vegetarian mom who had
more than Trace Amounts in her breast
milk had only been vegged for less than
a year but for some of these other toxic
pollutants the average vegetarian levels
were only one to two percent as high as
the average levels in the United States
breast is still best regardless of the
dietary pattern of the mother but
nursing infants of vegetarian women
whose diets are low on the food chain in
other words plant-based and the
advantage of being exposed to less
chemical pollution
[Music]
foreign